

Charles Mutie Mbillo

0111810434

mbillocharles@gmail.com

Nairobi

Nationality: Kenyan

Birthday: 17-07-1975

Website:

https://mbillocharles.netlify.app/

Marital Status: Married

Religion: Roman Catholic

Skill

Dart & Flutter

Canva

Django	•	•	♦		
Python	•	•	•		
JavaScript, PHP	•	•	•		
HTML 5	•	•	•	•	
CSS3, Bootstrap5, Tailwind	•	•	•		
SQL, MongoDB	♦	•	•		
React	♦	•			

Objective

Results-Driven IT Professional

As a seasoned IT professional with over a decade of experience, I bring a unique blend of technical expertise, business acumen, and passion for innovation to the table. With a strong background in Software Development, ITIL service management, and Cybersecurity. I excel in delivering high-quality solutions that drive business value streams as highlighted;

- 1. On-Demand IT Expertise;
- 2. Faster Adoption of New Technologies;
- 3. Outsourced Day-to-Day Support and IT Management;
- 4. Improved Security;
- 5. Business Continuity Benefits of Managed IT Services;
- 6. Training, Procurement, Installation and IT Support incl. smart phones/devices;
- 7. IT Consulting

Key Strengths

Key Strengths

- 1. Technical Expertise: Proficient in Django, Python, HTML, CSS, SQL and various IT tools and technologies.
- 2. Business Acumen: Strong understanding of business operations and the ability to align IT solutions with organizational goals.
- 3. Innovation: Passionate about staying up-to-date with the latest technologies and trends, with a focus on continuous improvement and innovation.
- 4. Leadership: Proven track record of leading cross-functional teams and mentoring junior professionals.

Projects

Web Application (Dev)

04/2024 - Nowadays

Sacco Transactions Web Application

A transactional application system, integrated with USSD platform (API) to post, fetch... transactions

Website Development (Dev)

04/2024 - Nowadays

SEO and Conversion Rate

Optimization(CRO)

Event Organiser's Website with SEO optimization, Conversion Rate Optimization (CRO) and Social Media Management

Kanban
♦
♦
♦

Trello
♦
♦
♦

MS Office Suite
♦
♦
♦

Google Suite
♦
♦
♦

MEAL
♦
♦
♦

Zoom &
♦
♦
♦

TeamViewer

Al Prompt
♦
♦

Engineering

Natural Learning
♦
♦

NL & Machine
Learning ML

Interest

Athletics, Agriculture

POS System Deployment (Dev/TechOps)

04/2024 - Nowadays

POS System Deployment

Procure, configure, install deploy Aronium Lite ... POS

Data Collection Application (DevOps)

04/2024 - Nowadays

Census Web App (offline/online)

Data Collection Web App (offline), Online visualization

Education

Software Development 02/2023 - Nowadays

Power Learn Project

Certificate of Achievement

ITIL v4 Foundation 11/2022 - Nowadays

Online - Distance Learning

Data Management, Virtual Assistant, 01/2022 - 12/2022

Digital Marketing & Content Writing |

Ajira Digital

Certificate of Completion

Diploma in Information Technology 06/2006 - 08/2008

Government Training Institute - GTI

EMBU

Work Experience

Self Employed (Saba7s Data Centre)

12/2012 - Nowadays

Website Dev & Founder

ICT Experience

- Software Development, Innovation, Value Streams exploitation.
- Managed Service Provider (MSP), ISP Reseller
- IT services such as Online Services (e.g. institutions and individual) GHRIS, E-citizen, BRS
- Data Management, Virtual Assistant, Digital Marketing, Content Writing & Translation
- Data storage, cloud integration, backup and restore
- Patching, disaster recovery, virtualization, and; Application and infrastructure management to provide connectivity.
- Business Continuity and Disaster Recovery (BCP&DRP), Redundancy Plans development
- Information Security protocols, Risk Assessment, Vulnerability, Penetration Testing

- Policy and procedure creation for security, cybersecurity, email, Internet usage, access control
- System Administration, help desk support, procurement, and technical issue resolution
- Networking, network monitoring, IoT installation, troubleshooting, and diagnostics
- Certified CCTV System Design, Implementation & Installation
- Handle the management of IT infrastructure; Offer technical support to staff; Manage user access accounts; Add cybersecurity software to IT
- Handle contract management; Offer compliance and risk management; and. Provide payroll services

GOK 06/2007 - 12/2007

Internship: Office of the President (Cabinet Office) - Public Service Reforms & Development Secretariat (PSR&DS)

Duties and achievements

- 1. Project Management (RRI)
- 2. Vision 2030 proofreading

Worldwide Logistics Ltd-JKIA

01/1998 - 10/2000

Assistant Manager

Assistant Manager Duties and achievements

- Customs and Statutory Procedures
- Air, Sea freight and Courier Services
- Foreign Missions, Relief Organizations, SEAT Rally team... Clientele

National Youth Service

05/1994 - 07/1996

Serviceman

- Service Man at Lomut Development Unit
- Service Man at NYS Engineering School

Duty/responsibility/achievement:

- Paramilitary and regimentation
- National building programs
- Technical and vocational training in various skills and trades

Activities

- 1. IEEE Computer Society Membership
- 2. Alumni community

Kioko Muema

Business Consultant

Tel: 0729024556

Sifa Robert

Shanzu TTC

Tel: 0728 330220

Rev. Fr. Raphael Nganga Roman Catholic Priest · Catholic Diocese of Machakos

Tel: 0729870764